Guide to the Harris-Oliphant papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Writings
  - Subseries III.2: Titled Prose A-Z
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Private Property and Social Life in the Light of Jesus", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., ca. 50 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Prophecy of Japan", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 3 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Republic is Old Empire in New Mask", [n.p.], 14 Sept [n.y.], (1 a.ms., 10 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Resurrection", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 8 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Savior Work in Hell", [n.p.], 1879, (1 t.ms., ca. 60 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake ["Some Ways of the Evil Woman"], [n.p.], 15 July 1879, (1 a.ms., 15 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake ["Spirit World"], [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., ca. 110 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Study of Occultism", [n.p.], May and June 1888, (1 t.ms., 59 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Survey of Swedenborg", [n.p.], 6 Mar 1877, (1 a.ms., & 1 t.ms., 64 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 5, 6)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Teachings from the Occult Ground", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 121 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Three Belief Sciences", Park Avenue, 17 Sept 1892, (1 a.ms., 4 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Three Chief Sciences", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 4 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "To the Beloved: Faithful in Affection", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., 2 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Touch of Arch-Nature", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 t.mss., & 1 set of carbons, 21 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 11, 12)
      [Version 3 is located in Box 21, Folder 24.]
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Truth and Life in Jesus", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 60 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Visitation" - Series 1 Nos. 1-23, Linn Lilla, 9 Nov 1890 - 1 Dec 1890, (1 a.ms., ca. 60 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Ways of the Evil Woman", [n.p.], 15 July 1877, (1 t.ms., 11 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake ["The Wisdom of the Adepts"], [n.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 270 pages a.ms., in 3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 16-18)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Wisdom of the Adepts" Vol II - "A Study of Elementaries", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., & 1 t.ms. & carbons, ca. 175 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 19-21)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "W.A." - ["The Wisdom of the Adepts"] 15th - 37th form, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., ca. 150 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake ["The Wisdom of the Adepts"], [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms. & carbons, ca. 1000 pages, in 5 folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-5)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Wisdom of Angels", New York, 1857, (1 t.ms., 9 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Wisdom of Angels", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 101 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Wisdom of Angels" - Appendix, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., ca. 15 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Words of Chrysanthea", Fountaingrove, Aug and Sept 1877, (1 a.ms., & 1 t.ms., ca. 56 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 10, 11)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Words of Chrysanthea to her Sisters", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 3 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Word from the Unseen", [n.p.], 1888, (1 a.ms., 4 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Subseries IIII.3: Unidentified Prose
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Unidentified Manuscripts, [v.p], [v.d.], (ca. 500 pages ms., in 19 folders) (Box 14, Folder 1-19)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Unidentified Manuscript, [Old Colwyn], 13 Apr 1892 - 25 June 1892, (1 a.ms., ca. 61 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Unidentified Manuscript - "The Key to the Gospel.. .", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 102 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Unidentified Manuscript, [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 150 pages ms., in 2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 22, 23)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Unidentified Manuscript, [n.p.], 7 Nov 1879 - 28 Dec 1879, (ca. 242 pages ms., in 1 folder) (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Unidentified Manuscript, [n.p.], [n.d.], (66 pages ms., in 1 folder) (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Unidentified Manuscript ConcerningNatural Associations and Procreations, [n.p.], 23 July 1877, (1 a.ms., 2 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Unidentified Manuscript, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 98 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Misc. Sheet, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 1 page, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Subseries IIII.4: Poetry
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Misc. Poetry "A-D", [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 30 pages ms., in 1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Advent Song", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., 32 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Misc. Poetry "E-G", [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 30 pages ms., in 1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Easter Lillies", [n.p.], 1892, (1 ms., 30 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Misc. Poetry "H-J", [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 30 pages ms., in 1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Hours with Destiny", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 52 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Echo of the Hills", [n.p.], 1889, (1 a.ms., & 1 t.ms., 11 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 7, 8)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Hours with Destiny", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., & 1 t.ms., ca. 100 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 9, 10)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Hymns of Fraternity", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., & 1 t.ms., ca. 100 pages, In 1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Misc. Poetry "L-N", [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 25 pages ms., in 1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Living Poesies", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., ca. 15 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Meditations of a Queen", [n.p.], Sept 1874, (1 a.ms., & 1 t.ms., ca. 300 pages, In 1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "New Year Song", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., & 2 t.mss, ca. 350 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 15, Folder 16-18)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Star-Flowers" - Cantos 8-10, plus Misc. Pages, [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 1500 pages t.ms., in 9 folders) (Box 16, Folder 1-9)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Misc. Poetry "O-R", [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 30 pages ms., in 1 folder) (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Misc. Poetry "S-U, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 5 pages ms., in 1 folder) (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Street - San Francisco", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., & 1 t.ms., 8 pages, In 2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 3, 4)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Misc. Poetry "V-W", [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 75 pages ms., in 1 folder) (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Visitations", Linn Lilla, 15-23 June 1890, (1 a.ms., & 2 t.mss., ca. 250 pages, In 3 folders) (Box 17, Folder 6-8)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "What Roses for the Pall", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 t.ms., 68 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Winter Song", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 a.ms., ca. 75 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Quotations and Excerpts, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 15 pages ms., in 1 folder) (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake Various Poems, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 bound volume, ca. 200 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Subseries IIII.5: Hymns
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Hymns given from the beginning", [Vinecliff], 1872, (1 bound volume, ca. 100 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Subseries IIII.6: Printed Material
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Arcana of Christianity: Genesis - Vol 1", New York, 1858, (45 pages photostat, in 1 folder) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Joy Bringer", [n.p.], 17-23 Feb 1886, (ca. 10 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "Star-Flowers" Cantos 1-4, 6, Fountaingrove, 1886, (5 bound volumes, ca. 350 pages, in 5 folders) (Box 17, Folder 14-18)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "A Voice from Heaven", [n.p.], 1879, (66 pages photostat, in 1 folder) (Box 21, Folder 25)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Wedding Guest", Fountain Grove, May 1877, (ca. 22 pages photostat, in 1 folder) (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Harris, Thomas Lake "The Wisdom of Angels", [n.p.], [1857], (ca. 40 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Lawton & Schneider's Notes and Research Files
  - Lawton, George Interviews on Harris, [n.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 40 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Lawton, George Letters to Lawton regarding Harris/Oliphant, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 150 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Lawton, George Notes by Lawton, [n.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 50 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Misc. Material - No direct Harris connection, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 50 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Lawton, George & H.L. Schneider Lawton & Schneider Notes - Harris and Related, [n.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 200 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Lawton, George & H.L. Schneider Schneider and Lawton's Correspondence on their Book about Harris, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 20 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - [Lawton, George] On the Chevaillier Case - Notes, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 20 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Articles and Pamphlets on T.L. Harris, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 50 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Material Used for Chapter XX of "The Gateway of the Comfortings", [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 50 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - [Lawton, George] Copied Source Material, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 500 pages, in 2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 10, 11)
  - [Lawton, George] Notes for Harris book, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 30 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - [Lawton, George] Notes and Copies of Extracts from Harris Books made in Santa Rosa, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 75 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Schneider, H.L. Notes for Chapter 1, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 40 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Lawton, George Notes about Harris from papers, etc., [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 50 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Templeton, James Murray Address Book (1891) and Diary (1881;1884), [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 30 pages, & 2 bound volumes, in 1 folder) (Box 19, Folder 5)
    [This folder is on Microfilm. MN#2001-3110-1]
  - Templeton, Rosamond Misc. Material, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 50 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Folder for Oliphant Material, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder, in 1 folder) (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Letters, articles, and photostats on Lawrence Oliphant and his writings, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 15 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Schneider, H.L. Misc. Schneider Notes - Chapter 2, [v.p.], [v.d.], (ca. 25 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Series V: Miscellaneous
  - [Markham, E.] [Dictation by E.M.], [n.p.], [v.d.], (1 a.ms., ca 25 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Papers on Japan (Vol. 3) from Seminars at Harvard University, Cambridge, MA, Nov 1965, (1 bound volume, 229 pages, in 1 folder) (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Series VI: Photographs
  - Negatives of Photos & List of Photos, [n.p.], [n.d.], (ca. 20 negatives, in 1 folder) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of: Jane L.W. Harris; The Hermitage, Linn Lilla; Unidentified horses and landscapes, [v.p.], [n.d.], (25 photographs, in 1 folder) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of T.L. Harris (same print), [n.p.], [n.d.], (18 photographs, in 1 folder) (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Photographs and Negatives of T.L. Harris; L. Oliphant; Alice Oliphant; Residence at Brocton, NY; Fountaingrove, [v.p.], [n.d.], (15 photographs & negatives, in 1 folder) (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Various Photographs, [v.p.], [n.d.], (14 photographs, in 1 folder) (Box 20, Folder 7)